<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 100: Cost and Usage Analysis on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/</link><description>Recent content in Level 100: Cost and Usage Analysis on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>View your AWS Invoices</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/1_view_invoice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/1_view_invoice/</guid><description>At the end of a billing cycle or at the time you make a purchase and incur a one-time fee, AWS charges the payment method you have and issues your invoice as a PDF file. You can view these invoices through the AWS console, which will show summary information of all usage and cost incurred for that one off item, or billing period.
Log into the console via SSO and go to the billing dashboard: Select Orders and invoices from the menu on the left: Click on an Invoice ID corresponding to the month you wish to view: It will download a PDF version of your invoice similar to below: function prevStep(){ window.</description></item><item><title>View your cost and usage in detail</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/2_cost_usage_detail/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/2_cost_usage_detail/</guid><description>You can view past and present costs and usage through the console, which also provides more detailed information on cost and usage. We will go through accessing your cost and usage by service, and by linked account (if applicable). We will then drill down into a specific service.
Go to the billing dashboard: Click on Bills from the left menu: Select the Date you require from the drop down menu, by clicking on the menu item: You will be shown Bill details by service, where you can dynamically drill down into the specific service cost and usage.</description></item><item><title>Download your monthly cost and usage file</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/3_cost_usage_download/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/3_cost_usage_download/</guid><description>It is possible to download a CSV version of your summary cost and usage information. This can be accessed by a spreadsheet application for ease of use. We will download your monthly usage file and view it.
Go to the billing dashboard: Click on Bills from the left menu: Select the Date you require from the drop down menu, by clicking on the menu item: Click on Download CSV: It will download a CSV version of the bill you can use in a spreadsheet application.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/4_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/4_tear_down/</guid><description>There is no configuration performed within this lab, so no teardown is required.
function prevStep(){ window.open("..\/3_cost_usage_download\/", "_self") } function nextStep(){ window.open("\/cost\/", "_self") } function togglePopup(){ document.getElementById("prevnext-1").classList.toggle("active"); } X Congratulations! Now that you have completed the lab, if you have implemented this knowledge in your environment, you should re-evaluate the questions in the Well-Architected tool. This lab specifically helps you with COST1 - &amp;ldquo;How do you implement cloud financial management?</description></item></channel></rss>