<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 100: Cost and Usage Governance on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/</link><description>Recent content in Level 100: Cost and Usage Governance on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create and implement an AWS Budget for monthly forecasted cost</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/1_budget_forecast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/1_budget_forecast/</guid><description>Budgets allow you to manage cost and usage by providing notifications when cost or usage are outside of configured amounts. They cannot be used to restrict actions, only notify on usage after it has occurred.
Budgets and notifications are updated when your billing data is updated, which is at least once per day.
NOTE: You may not receive an alarm for a forecasted budget if your account is new. Forecasting requires existing usage within the account.</description></item><item><title>Create and implement an AWS Budget for EC2 actual cost</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/2_budget_ec2actual/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/2_budget_ec2actual/</guid><description>We will create a monthly EC2 actual cost budget, which will notify if the actual costs of EC2 instances exceeds the specified amount.
Click Create budget: Select Cost budget, and click Set your budget &amp;gt;: Create a cost budget, enter the following details:
Name: EC2_actual Period: Monthly Budget effective dates: Recurring Budget Start Month: (current month) Budget amount: Fixed Budgeted amount: $1 (enter an amount a lot LESS than last months cost), Other fields: leave a defaults Under FILTERING click on Service: Type Elastic in the search field, then select the checkbox next to EC2-Instances(Elastic Compute Cloud - Compute) and Click Apply filters: De-select Upfront reservation fees, and click Configure alerts &amp;gt;: Select:</description></item><item><title>Create and implement an AWS Budget for EC2 Savings Plan coverage</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/3_budget_spcoverage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/3_budget_spcoverage/</guid><description>We will create a monthly savings plan coverage budget which will notify if the coverage of Savings Plan for EC2 is below the specified amount.
You should not set an arbitrary limit to alarm on (i.e. alarm if coverage is less than 80%) instead select your current level of coverage - so if coverage reduces, you can act and increase coverage if required.
From the AWS Budgets dashboard in the console, click Create budget: Select Savings Plans budget, and click Set your budget &amp;gt;: Create a cost budget, enter the following details:</description></item><item><title>Create and implement an AWS Budget Report</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/4_budget_report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/4_budget_report/</guid><description>AWS Budgets Reports allow you to create and send daily, weekly, or monthly reports to monitor the performance of your AWS Budgets.
From the Budgets dashboard, Click on Budgets Reports: Click Create budget report: Create a report with the following details:
Report name: WeeklyBudgets Select all budgets Click Configure delivery settings &amp;gt;: Configure the delivery settings:
Report frequency: Weekly Day of week: Monday Email recipients: Click Confirm budget report &amp;gt;: Review the configuration, click Create: Your budget report should now be complete: You should receive an email similar to the one below: You have created a budget report.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/5_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/5_tear_down/</guid><description>Delete a budget report We will delete the bugdet report.
From the Budgets Reports dashboard, click on the three dots next to the Weekly Budgets budget report, and click Delete: You can see there are no budget reports: Delete a budget We will delete all three budgets that we configured.
From the Budgets dashboard, click the three dots next to the budget CostBudget1, click Delete: Do the same for the budgets EC2_actual and SP_Coverage</description></item></channel></rss>